Aren't you gonna wash your hands
before you eat?
No, I wrap the toilet paper on my fingers
like an oven mitt.
You could catch a puck with it.
So, Mom, what brings you
to our neck of the woods?
I'm showing a house down the beach,
thought I'd swing by and see my grandson.
Ta-da!
- Nice house?
- Oh, magnificent.
Priced to move. The owner lost everything
in the stock market, killed himself.
- Oh, that's terrible.
- He didn't do it in the house. Thank God.
Even with an ocean view,
suicide homes are a bitch to unload.
Keep that in mind
you wanna teach your brother a lesson.
Thanks for the tip.
Good morning, Alan.
Morning, Jake.
Satan.
Good morning, darling.
Two coffee cups?
- Did you have a friend spend the night?
- Yes, I did.
Couldn't get her to stand on the trap door,
huh?
Charlie, I don't have time for coffee,
so...
- Oh. Hello.
- Hello.
Uh, Chelsea, this is my mother.
Mom, this is Chelsea.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Welcome back to the States.
Thank you.
Where have I been?
Charlie says you have a place in Italy-
You know, Chelsea. Sometimes
when I'm drunk, I make up stories, so...
You know, grain of salt.
That is quite an engagement ring.
Thank you.
Does your fiancé know about this one?
My fiancé is this one.
You want me put this in a travel mug?
You didn't tell your mother
we're engaged?
If she hadn't sold me the house,
she wouldn't even know where I live.
When were you gonna tell her about me?
At the wedding?
Well, technically,
I think we have up to a year after that.
Shame on you. I am so sorry.
It's all right, dear. I'm used to it.
Although a phone call
would have been nice.
It's good to meet you. Excuse me.
So yea or nay on the travel mug?
Charlie, you broke
your mother's heart.
How is that funny?
It's not. Guys, a little respect.
What is wrong with you?
Same stuff as always, nothing new.
Does this smell like butt to you?
CHARLIE:
I'm glad you came over.
That was the plan, wasn't it?
Yeah, but I thought you might
still be angry with me.
I'm not angry, Charlie.
I'm just disappointed.
Gee, I'd kind of prefer it
if you were angry.
Why?
Because angry sex is hot.
Disappointed sex is-
Well, we might as well be married.
Just brush your teeth.
Brushing.
Look, I understand you have
a difficult relationship with your mom.
Uh-huh.
But it make things kind of tough on me.
Hey, I don't expect you to dislike her
right away.
Give it time, let it happen naturally.
That's not funny.
If I'm gonna marry into your family,
I want us to act like a family.
Care for each other.
With my family, it's kind of either-or.
Let me put it this way.
I'm taking your mother
to lunch on Thursday.
You're doing what?
I'm not going to participate
in this childish little feud of yours.
It's not a childish feud.
Boy.
What's wrong with me having a warm
and healthy relationship with your mother?
Well, for starters, you'll be the only one.
Ever.
Oh, don't be so dramatic.
No, no. No. No.
I'm not being dramatic enough.
I should be wearing tights
and holding a skull.
- Preferably hers.
- It's just lunch.
That's what Hitler said
to Czechoslovakia.
Hitler said "It's just lunch?"
Well, he said it in German.
Watch the History Channel.
Charlie, I'm not doing this to hurt you.
By my spending time with your mother
I can get a better understanding of you.
Chelsea, trust me.
Any insight you gain into me
via my mother...
...will end our relationship faster than
catching me in bed with a farm animal.
Just relax. It'll be fine.
That's what Hitler said to Poland.
And for the record...
...as long as we've been going out,
I've never met your mother.
My mother's in Illinois.
Oh, yeah, and my mother's in "Italy."
My mother really lives in Illinois.
And besides, when you meet her...
...you will count your blessings
you have your mom.
Tell you what, I'll trade you,
sight unseen, my mom for yours.
- Charlie-
- I'll throw in Alan and a couple of steaks.
Come here.
No. I don't wanna.
I'm too upset.
Okay. Good night.
I'm sorry, I can't separate my emotions
from my body.
I understand.
I don't wanna punish you.
If my heart's not in it...
...then it's just my penis
going through the motions.
Well, we certainly wouldn't want that.
Good night.
Chelsea.
I'm not upset anymore.
Charlie, I'm sleeping.
I know.
Can you just wake up enough
so it's not weird?
Never mind. Sweet dreams.
Okay, let me remind you...
...this is Malibu beachfront property.
The previous owner
had a spectacular view...
...as he filled his pockets with rocks
and jumped into the pool.
- Mom?
- Hang on.
No, it's not a suicide home.
At most, it's suicide adjacent.
All right, get back to me.
What are you doing here?
What, I can't come visit
my mother at work?
Well, I suppose you could, but I've been
here for 22 years, and you never have.
Well, maybe if you validated parking...
Or any part of my life.
What do you want, Charlie?
Okay, first of all, I wanna apologize
for not telling you about Chelsea...
...and the engagement.
I know that was wrong
and selfish of me.
Thank you.
Good.
I'm glad we got that out of the way.
So I understand
you guys are having lunch tomorrow.
Yes, we are. Is that a problem?
No, no. No, it's great.
I came all the way here and paid for
my own parking to tell you it's great.
Uh-huh.
All right.
Let's put our cards on the table.
What's your angle?
Angle?
I have no angle.
Yeah, and I have no hangover.
Look, Charlie.
If you're really gonna marry this woman...
...I wanna get started on the right foot.
I don't wanna make the mistake
I made with Alan's wife, June.
- Judith.
- Oh, whatever.
Heinous woman.
The fact remains, had I overlooked that...
...and welcomed her,
she wouldn't have kept me at arms length...
...during Jake's formative years,
and I'd have a better relationship with him.
- You want a better relationship with him?
- Not the way he is now.
But if I'd gotten to him earlier...
...he wouldn't have the manners
of an outhouse rat.
So bottom line, you want a good
relationship with Chelsea...
...so you get your hooks
into the next generation?
Can't I just wanna be a loving mother
and grandmother?
Well, I suppose you could, but I've been
here 40 years, and you never have.
Evelyn Harper.
Oh. Hello, Dr. Yakimura. What's up?
Oh, that is good news.
What's the address?
Nice neighborhood. Thanks for the tip.
What's the good news?
Massive coronary in Brentwood.
Six bedrooms, four baths...
...and a fully-equipped gym
the fat idiot shouldn't have been using.
Excuse me.
Mommy has to fly faster
than the other vultures.
Your mother took me
to the most adorable little restaurant.
No kidding.
It's called Mon Grenier Du Vivre.
You know what that means?
Probably "The Spider's Web."
Charlie.
"The Devil's Barbecue"?
Be nice.
Sorry.
"Bitch in the Box."
- So, what did you guys talk about?
- You know, everything.
She's so smart and funny.
She's been through so much.
She's a real survivor.
Just remember, in order for her
to be a survivor, others had to die.
Okay, that's enough.
Your mom's a terrific lady.
I'm starting to think
any problem you have with her...
...is your problem, not hers.
Oh, damn, it's too late.
You're infected with the virus.
Stop it.
I'm sorry, but when you fall asleep tonight,
I'm gonna have to set you on fire.
Shut up.
Believe me, when you meet my mom,
you'll thank God for Evelyn.
What the hell is your mom...
...a rabid werewolf
that craps hot lava on people?
Never mind about my mother.
Let's play.
I don't know.
What's the matter?
All this talk about mothers,
I'm not in the mood.
Bet I could get you in the mood.
Maybe, but it would be
a cheap manipulation.
All right, but don't come
rubbing up against me in the night.
I won't.
Fine. Good night.
Good night.
Don't even think about it.
Listen, you gotta do me a favor.
That's what I live for.
Sarcasm is for winners, Alan.
What can I do for you?
Chelsea's somehow gotten it into her head
that mom is, you know, human.
You need to set her straight.
- Why don't you set her straight?
- She doesn't believe me.
Probably because I turned out okay.
She needs to hear from somebody
whose life is wrecked and unsalvageable.
I.e., you.
Thanks.
And what do you expect me to say?
I don't know, just tell her
about your phobias, your obsessions...
...your failures: work, marriage,
and parenthood. She'll connect the dots.
You know what? I think I'll pass.
Oh, come on.
I always back you up when you need me.
When have you ever backed me up?
Okay,
let's stay focused on my problems.
I'm not gonna argue
we didn't have a difficult childhood...
...but really, who had a good one?
Isn't it time we forgive and forget?
Where's this coming from?
No, I'm just saying
that maybe our lives would be richer...
...if we let go of this pointless resentment
toward our mother...
...and just move on with our lives.
She got to you, didn't she?
- What are you talking about?
- What did she do?
Pay off your car?
Get that dead black tooth fixed?
Listen to yourself.
I have to go to work.
- Hold it.
- What?
- Your watch.
- What about it?
It doesn't have Hamburglars
on the wrist band.
So?
- Let me see it.
- No, it's mine.
CHARLIE:
Let me see it.
This is a Rolex.
You sold me out for a watch.
Hey, I did not sell you out for a watch.
I sold you out
for a Swiss chronometer.
Stainless steel submariner,
waterproof to up to 300 meters.
And look, it winds itself.
Put it on your right arm, it'll run forever.
Oh, good thinking.
Oh, hey, look, what else I got?
Genuine porcelain veneer.
From an English-speaking dentist.
"From an English-speaking dentist."
Hey, Jake. I need a favor.
Sorry, I can't say bad things
about Grandma.
Okay. What did she buy you?
New guitar? Mini bike?
Pizza.
You sold me out for a pizza?
Not just a pizza, a meat lovers pizza.
M is for the misery she caused me
O is for the other things she did
T is for the traitor who's my brother
H is for the hump who is his kid
No, it's true.
They can bleach anything these days.
Really?
It's gotta burn like hell.
Like a lit cigar.
But it's worth it.
Curb appeal isn't just for the front door.
E is for extremely frightening girl talk
- Oh, hey, honey.
- How was shopping?
Mom, pick up any new souls?
Charlie, that's uncalled for.
It's okay, Chelsea.
He can't help himself.
Yes, he can.
There's no excuse
for speaking to your mother that way.
You don't know that.
Evelyn, thank you for a wonderful day.
Pleasure was mine.
It's nice to be appreciated for a change.
- We on for yoga tomorrow?
- Can't wait.
Oh, and, of course, you and Charlie
are coming for dinner on Saturday.
- We wouldn't miss it.
- Um, um...
Actually...
...Chels, we have plans on Saturday,
remember?
- What plans?
- Oh, for God sake, can't you just play along?
- We'll be there.
- Wonderful. Ta-ta.
- You proud of yourself?
- Not really, I lost that one.
R is for the rifle in my mouth
Put them all together they spell "mother"
A word that's only half of how I feel
Hello.
I am Alan Cousteau.
I left the Calypso...
...at 0500 hours...
...and have descended
to a depth of 60 fathoms.
And yet my Rolex
is keeping perfect time.
Oh, look...
...there goes a giant squid.
Alan?
Yes?
What are you doing?
Um...
I got no good answer.
It's Saturday night, and I'm all alone.
Do you know where Charlie is?
We're supposed to be at your mother's at 7.
Oh. You are cutting it close.
Have you seen him?
Not for a
couple hours. Have you tried his cell?
I did, there's no answer.
I'm getting worried.
CHARLIE: Chelsea, I'm home.
- Thank goodness.
I return to the deep.
Where have you been?
Picking up a little surprise for you.
Come on in.
- Mom?
- Hello, sweetie. Oh. Ooh.
Feels like you gave up
on the Jenny Craig, huh?
- What are you doing here?
- I flew her in from Illinois.
First class, very swanky.
Of course, I had some rich Jew lawyer
chewing my ear off the whole way.
Tell her about the food.
Oh, the food was terrific...
...but the flight attendant
was a colored homo.
Really, I'm glad they make them pick up
the dinner rolls with tongs...
...because I can't risk the AIDS.
I hope you didn't fill up.
We're going for dinner.
Oh, how nice.
Now, be honest with me, Charlie.
You're so dark and handsome,
you gotta have some dago in you, right?
God, I love your mom.
That was the worst dinner of my life.
Really? I thought the two moms hit it off.
Kind of country mouse, city mouse.
I especially liked the part
when country mouse kicked off her shoes...
...put her big yellow bunions up
on city mouse's mahogany coffee table...
...and asked her how she liked
having a commie Arab for a president.
You've made your point, Charlie.
Point? Whatever do you mean?
You leave my mother alone,
and I'll leave yours alone.
Well, gosh, I don't know.
I've really taken a shine to your mom.
She promised to teach me
how to chew tobacco and burn a cross.
Do we have a deal or not?
Deal. Come here.
I'm not in the mood.
All right.
But don't be rubbing up against me
in the middle of the night.
Don't worry, I won't.
Good night.
All right, I was bluffing.
Feel free to rub.
Rub yourself.
Chels?
What?
Can you watch me so it's not weird?